STANDARD FOR LIFE
Good morning, Church!
[Good morning.]
You may be seated. Thank you.
Hallelujah.
[Amen.]
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers, we recognise you; wherever you are, whatever position you are in, Jesus knows better.
Amen.
[Amen.]
Hallelujah.
Today we will look at some challenges that relationships face.
The book of Romans 12:1-2, "Therefore, I urge you, brothers and sisters, in view of God's mercy,
to offer your bodies as a living sacrifice, holy and pleasing to God -
this is your true and proper worship.
Do not conform to the pattern of this world, but be transformed by the renewing of your mind.
Then you will be able to test and approve what God's will is - His good, pleasing and perfect will."
Let me take you to the verse 19 there.
Romans 12:19-20, "Do not take revenge, my dear friends, but leave room for God's wrath,
for it is written: 'It is mine to avenge; I will repay, 'says the Lord.
On the contrary: 'If your enemy is hungry, feed him; if he is thirsty, give him something to drink.
In doing this, you will heap burning coals on his head.'"
I will take the last verse now - verse 21 says:
"Do not be overcome by evil, but overcome evil with good" - Romans 12:21.
When you look at the book of Proverbs 10:12:
"Hatred stirs up conflict, but love covers all wrongs."
Countless Christians are imprisoned by offences.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Because of wounds and hurts which offences have caused in our lives,
most of us cannot function properly in our profession.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You can do better than now, but because of offences you find that you cannot function properly
in your profession; I mean, in your working place.
You cannot function properly.
Wherever you look: offences.
Offence has become an epidemic, everywhere.
Suddenly, your boss at your working place says, "OK, I demote you".
What have I done?
Suddenly, you see your inferior being asked to supervise you.
Someone whom you were sending on errands in your working place, your junior,
someone you trained over time to become what he is.
Now, your boss gives instruction that this someone will supervise you and you are to submit to him.
How would you take that?
Someone, whom you have trained over time in your working place, will become your supervisor
because he is related to the owner of the company.
Suddenly, instruction will just come for him to become your supervisor and you are to submit to him.
This person will suddenly change his tactic and strategy.
Before, he was submissive to you, but after becoming your boss, he would avoid you.
He will be sending instructions to you through someone.
How would you take it?
At the conference you will find him sitting in front of you, in the position of boss, giving instructions.
You know how they look like,
"Yes, this is very important. We should carry out this instruction..."
You know - there are "dark shades" nowadays.
Do you know "dark shades"?
OK, when you don't want to see someone around you, you put on "dark shades".
He will now begin to say, "Yes, we have to take the instruction.
The head of marketing (he is referring to you) should immediately tomorrow make sure
that this department is being supervised, and he should submit the form and report to me the next day.
Thank you. This is just an instruction I wanted to give you".
He will stand up.
But if the boss has not gone, you cannot stand up.
You cannot leave or stand up at the same time as your boss.
He has to leave.
Because of wounds and hurts which offences have caused in our lives,
most of us cannot function properly in our profession.
Each time you carry out an assignment, you will remember someone you trained.
You will not want to give your best, and your best is needed.
You begin to think.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We cannot function properly because we are holding someone hostage of unforgiveness.
Tell your neighbour:
It is difficult.
We carry anger, hatred, bitterness, and hurt against someone.
You believe you can function properly when you are carrying anger and hatred.
That is self-imprisonment.
Self what?
Self-imprisonment.
It is not that we are asked to go to prison, but many of us are in prison.
And it is a most serious prison.
When we talk of prison, we only think about those who are inside the physical prison.
There are countless people...
90% of the whole world are in what?
[In prison]
Self-imprisonment.
Many are victims of self-imprisonment.
You are imprisoned by anger, hatred, bitterness, hurt and unforgiveness.
Offence imprisons countless Christians, severs relationships
and widens the existing breaches between us.
Unless we release ourselves, God will not hear us.
We are hindered and handicapped from fulfilling our full potential.
To hold an offence against someone hinders and handicaps us from fulfilling our full potential.
Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold an offence, as a Christian.
Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold an offence against someone.
Listen to our Lord's prayer - we don't take it seriously.
It is fundamental.
When you wake up in the morning to walk with Jesus - this is fundamental.
Remember the Lord's prayer.
He said, "Forgive us as we forgive those who sin against us".
Have you? Do you forgive?
"Daily bread" means each day has its own grace.
Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold an offence against someone.
Some of our offences emanate from our close and dearest ones.
The higher the expectation, the greater the fall.
Tell your neighbour, "The higher the expectation, the greater the fall".
Some of our offences emanate from our close and dear ones such as father, mother, wife, husband or children.
The book of Psalm 55 - I will take my reading from verse 12,
"If an enemy were insulting me, I could endure it".
I like that.
"But it is you, a man like myself, my companion, my close friend." – Psalm 55:13
Did you listen to that?
Some of our offences emanate from our close and dearest ones.
If my enemy had offended me, I would not have bothered
but for you, my close friend, a man of my equal, my companion, my acquaintance.
Our families and our homes, which are meant to be a source of inspiration,
protection, provision and growth, where we learn to give love and receive love,
are often the very root of our pain -
brother against brother, father against brother, son against father and mother against son.
Battlefield of fight – family, home, a fellow Christian brother, a close friend, companion.
Rise up, and let us pray.
You want to release yourself by forgiving those who have wronged you.
Release yourself by forgiving those who have wronged you.
Begin to release yourself by forgiving those who have wronged you and promise that you will do restitution.
Prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Right now, begin to release yourself.
Promise you will do restitution.
Open your lips, viewers all over the world.
Those who have wronged you in one form or another.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers all over the world, I release you, in the name of Jesus from the pain of the past!
I release you from deep hurt – be released!
I release you, in the name of Jesus!
Viewers, once again, listen:
I release you, in the name of Jesus from the pain of the past!
Be released, in the name of Jesus!
Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold onto an offence.
I release you, in the name of Jesus!
Be released, in the name of Jesus!
Pray Along With Prophet T.B. Joshua - Touch Your Screen By Faith In Jesus' Name
Countless people, I mean, countless Christians are imprisoned by offence.
It is a trap; it is an effective instrument used by satan.
I release you, in the name of Jesus!
If you are a victim, I release you, in the name of Jesus!
Be released!
Pray Along With Prophet T.B. Joshua - Touch Your Screen By Faith In Jesus' Name
Release yourself – this is the key.
Release yourself; whether you are wrong or right, you have no right to hold onto an offence.
Right now, release yourself by forgiving those who have wronged you in one form or another.
You have been imprisoning yourself for so long.
You have been imprisoning yourself – blessing has been looking for you but you are in the prison.
Victory has been looking for you for so long but you are in the prison.
Deliverance has been looking for you but you are in the prison.
Healing has been looking for you for so long but you are in the prison.
Promotion you are looking for has been looking for you for so long whereas you are in the prison.
Self-imprisonment -
you create that; you put yourself in the prison.
You say, "I'm right. They abuse me. They misjudge me."
Healing you are looking for has been looking for you for so long now, whereas you are in the prison.
You have to release yourself.
When you release yourself - that is the key - then they will find you.
Offence imprisons countless Christians, severs relationships
and widens the existing breaches between us.
There is trouble already, before that offence comes.
When the offence now comes...
Our Lord's prayer - "Forgive us" - this is what you ask God for, but He gives us a condition;
"I will forgive you only if you can forgive others".
That is the condition He gave you.
The condition is: "I will forgive you as far as you are ready to forgive others".
Those who wronged you - whether you are wrong or right...
Tell your neighbour, "You have been imprisoning yourself for so long".
Tell your neighbour.
Say, "I have been imprisoning myself for so long".
God says, "I will not do for you what you can do yourself".
You say, "It is difficult for me".
No. You have to.
He will not do for you what you can do yourself.
When you release yourself, healing, deliverance and protection will find you.
Just name it.
That is my secret.
That is the secret to move forward now because you have imprisoned yourself.
You made a promise you failed to fulfill.
We made a vow we failed to fulfill – "Forgive me, Lord, as I forgive those who sin against me."
When you are not forgiving others, what you are asking Him, He will not give.
I want everyone to open his mouth and say,
"Forgive me as I forgive those who sin against me".
Did you?
You know the meaning of covenant.
People pay with their blood when they break a covenant in this world.
Covenant keeping God
There is no one like You
Alpha Omega
Covenant keeping God
There is no one like You
Alpha Omega
Covenant keeping God
There is no one like You
Alpha Omega
Covenant keeping God
There is no one like You
Alpha Omega
Covenant keeping God
There is no one like You
Alpha Omega
It is a testament - meaning covenant.
The word testament.
You are holding someone hostage of unforgiveness.
Tell your neighbour.
Say, "I am holding someone hostage of unforgiveness".
Tell yourself.
[I am holding someone hostage of unforgiveness.]
I cannot hear you.
Viewers, listen to me.
You are holding someone hostage of unforgiveness.
What do I mean, viewers?
I mean, you carry anger, hurt, bitterness, envy and jealousy against someone.
To hold an offence against someone hinders and handicaps us from fulfilling our full potential.
You see that there is a restriction; the key is to release yourself.
To release yourself is your role.
Be released, in the name of Jesus, from the pain of the past!
Whether you are right or wrong – be released!
Hurt, deep hurt – be released!
Be released!
Viewers all over the world, I release you in the name of Jesus, from the pain of the past, from hurt, deep hurt -
be released!
I release you, in the name of Jesus!
Viewers, once again, listen – I release you, in the name of Jesus, from the pain of the past, from hurt -
I mean, deep hurt - be released, in the name of Jesus!
Whether you are right or wrong, you have no right to hold onto an offence.
I release you, in the name of Jesus!
Be released, in the name of Jesus!
Countless people – I mean, countless Christians are imprisoned by offence.
It's a trap; it's an effective instrument used by satan.
I release you, in the name of Jesus!
If you are a victim,
Be released!
In the name of Jesus!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It's not too late; God's time is the best.
Now, you are released.
[Amen!]
Say, "I'm released!"
Begin to rejoice in your release!
Rejoice.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I'm guilty of hatred and unforgiveness.
I'm holding many people hostage but I never knew because when some certain things happened to me,
instead of me to let go of that particular thing, I would just continue to hold onto that.
I never knew it would be like this; I don’t understand.
I think the problem is from upbringing.
Did you listen to that?
He knows the value of what we are talking about.
He knows where he is supposed to have been.
Many of us don't understand what we are talking about.
When you know where you are supposed to be and you are not there, it's very painful.
Look at me.
I - T.B. Joshua - revelation concerning my future has kept on coming to me for the last 35 years.
Imagine I am not where God wants me to be today.
I don't know what would have happened to me.
It is because we don't have revelation about ourselves.
You don't know what God has in store for you.
If you have been dreaming, seeing where God is taking you to and you are not there,
and you know this is where you are supposed to be but you are not there,
you will take the issue seriously.
Have you released yourself now?
Yes, man of God.
You have released yourself.
Yes.
Let's carry on.
The more your pain, the greater your experience.
You stayed so long in the same class.
In each class at university, you are supposed to spend one year, but you have a carry-over - a retake -
and you spend three years in the same class.
If you are serious, you would be more intelligent and wiser and learn a lot of lessons.
I think it is not too bad if you stayed long in a class.
You need to learn what you need to know before getting to where God wants you to be.
If not, you will be dislodged and replaced by satan.
Tell your neighbour, "You need to learn enough experience. If not, you will be dislodged –
I mean, replaced by satan".
You need to know the pain of being a poor man so as to maintain the position of a rich man.
You need to know the pain of being a sick man so as to maintain the position of good health.
You need to know the pain of being disappointed so as to maintain the position of appointment.
Brother - you are released.
[Amen.]
And I want to assure you - you are released.
Thank You, Lord.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from The Synagogue Church of all Nations.
Emmanuel TV – Changing lives, Changing nations and Changing the world.